It's the very end of summer, hot and
dry.  But there is a scent in the air,
soft and easy to overlook, of
pine, sage and something else.  The
slightest hint of a cool autumn
approaching.  You can feel it in the
mornings, fresh and soft.  It's
stimulating, because after
spring it's definitely my
favorite time of year.  But this place
is not perfect;  Is any of them?  I traveled a
lot as a child in a military family,
and I can say that nowhere I
lived was everything rosy.
People here are upset about change,
frustrated, and have strong opinions, and
you would find those feelings in
most places.  You, oh, heat
.  Wherever you land, there's
trouble somewhere.  where something
is not entirely perfect.  Here,
as in many places, we strive to
create affordable housing opportunities
for young
workers.  They are
desperately needed in our shops and
supermarkets to keep
businesses afloat, but they can't find
anywhere to live.  And even if they could, they can
barely afford it working
full time.  It's a
common problem in many communities, but
especially after the lockdown, it
became clear how much we need
workers to thrive.  And
yet, houses and rentals are becoming
increasingly expensive.  In
my small town, if we don't have
anyone to run the supermarket, it's
a big problem because it's the only one
we have.  I remember once noticing
that there was no milk in the
refrigerated section.  I asked and was told
that the product was available, but there was no
one to put it on the
shelves.  As one of the
lucky families who found a way to
make ends meet, my
heart aches for my colleagues and I
worry about the future.  I know it's a
problem that both
cities and suburban areas are facing right now
.  But it's very true here
too.  I have incredible respect and
admiration for all these
families who get creative and
desperately try to find
new solutions.  I recently read
Jane Goodall's book on hope
and she made a very
important point.  When we look outward at
all that is wrong, we feel
overwhelmed.  But when we look at
our families, friends, and
local community, we see opportunities to
help, even in a small
way.  One concern that comes to
mind regarding rural life
is health.  My recent visit to the
emergency room highlighted the fact
that if you need more help than
a clinic can offer, you may have to
drive to a hospital 1
to 2 hours away.  It's a long
wait.  I know that sometimes people
move if they have serious health problems
.  So I am
deeply grateful that I
currently have good health and
physical ability and don't have to
worry about that.  But I know that, for
example, if I had a child with
health problems or if I myself
faced one in the future, it might
not be sustainable to live here.  And for
that reason, I am grateful every day that
I can walk through the forest next to my
home.  Throughout history,
communities have never been exempt from
facing difficulties at some
point.  And for that reason, we
desperately need to find ways to
enjoy today.  Because life keeps
throwing challenges at us.  And when we
feel overwhelmed is when we most
need to cultivate that
deep purpose and inner richness that
reminds us that there is often some
small way to improve our
daily experience despite the challenges
.  My recent health problem made me
very aware of the fact that,
even if everything outside of me is fine,
one day I may contract an
illness, lose someone I love, and
today needs to be lived.  My cat
is making a lot of noise.  I'm sorry.
I was hesitant to make a video about
this topic for a long time because I did
n't want to seem negative, as if I was
focusing too much on the challenges
my community faces.  On second thought
, I simply thought it would be a
very interesting topic to discuss, with the
caveat that all
communities face challenges, and I believe it
is fruitful.  You know, of
course, how to approach them.  I thought it would be
, you know, valuable to share these
things and raise awareness about them,
while showing that I obviously love my
home and my valley, and that I care about
these issues.  And that's why I
work hard every day to try to
support my community in any way I
can.  For example, something that has always
been difficult for me to understand is
when, uh, people move to a
rural area and yet have no
interest in understanding the ecosystem they
live in, or the more
natural aspect of the place where they live, or in
worrying about preserving it,
by building their houses and living in
a way that can try to
minimize their impact on the land.  There are
many people who simply don't
have that on their radar.  I could get
frustrated by that and let it, you
know, affect my mindset.  But
instead, I think it's just a challenge and
a motivator to get involved in my
local conservation group which, you
know, reaches so many people and tries to
educate and inspire them, you know, to
live a little more in tune with the
earth through small,
sustainable changes.  I think that's what
matters, because I think choosing
bitterness would be easier, because it's
like an excuse for me.  At least if
I think about it that way, it's a reason
not to help, not to get involved, and, you
know, not to try to improve where I live;
And that's simply not a mindset
that works for me.  It is certainly not
a mindset that leads me to
fulfillment and joy.  So I
really care a lot, you know, about
addressing these things and helping in
any way I can.  Sometimes
communities can be more open to
new people and new types of people
, and sometimes they are not.  I know there is a
challenge here because my community sees the
importance of having young people
working to keep businesses
thriving.  But many people
are also deeply concerned about
losing the small-town atmosphere and
seeing so much change happen in such a short
period of time.  These are all
understandable concerns, you know,
and for me, I know that change is
inevitable.  I think that's particularly
because I'm currently living
through a time of great change.  And it's
so inspiring, but also
overwhelming at times.  And I've simply had to
learn to, you know,
accept it.  There is often a
positive side to most
changes and modifications in a
community.  So I think it's
important for me to look for the
positive and negative aspects of everything,
really weigh them up, and understand a little
better what's happening around me.  And,
of course, to challenge my way of
thinking and to deeply consider
perspectives that are not naturally my own
.  Another very obvious challenge
that this community and
countless other communities face.  You could
argue that all communities
now face the impact of
climate change and this area is really no
different.  I love showcasing the
beauty of this valley in my videos.  And I
work to support
wildlands in this area.  But
last year we had the National Guard on
our doorstep, you know, fighting
raging wildfires.  And
although there is a great awareness that
wildfires are, in many
ways, a fairly natural part of
this area, you know, what we are
seeing now is truly
unprecedented.  And when you see the
destruction, when you live through that moment
and see the impact it has on people,
and you know that this won't be the last
time you feel this way, it can be
very overwhelming and frightening.  You know,
especially for someone who is just
starting out in life.  Although I don't plan on
making many videos in the future, you
know, obviously focusing on these
things, I think it's very important to
use it to inspire action.  And
you know, whether you donate a little or a lot
to charities and
non-profit organizations trying to make
a difference, whatever you can
contribute is more than enough.  And whatever
you can do in your
local community to help protect
your natural areas or those of other
places that you care about, that's all we
need to do.  And for me, that's how I
see it.  We just need to do what
we can.  So, yes, I hope you
found this interesting.
Perhaps I provided some
insights into my community and
many other communities that you may not
have considered before.  I think I'm
obviously mentioning things that
mean a lot to me as an
individual.  I am not an expert on any
of these topics.  I see so many young people and
young families with really
young children out here, being
really innovative and figuring out
how to make things work.  And it
's very inspiring and very incredible.  And
I want every young person, every child, to
feel that way.  You know, they can create
that change.  Anyway, I send you all my
love and see you very soon.
Take care.  Bye bye.